aaaa.org 2019-04-30

# Privacy Policy - 4A's

###### Effective Date: 12/09/18

Thank you for visiting the website of the 4A’s—the American Association of Advertising Agencies (“4A’s,” “we,” “our,” or “us”) and reviewing our privacy policy.  We provide this policy to describe how we collect, use, share, and otherwise process information that you and others provide us through [www.aaaa.org](http://https.www.aaaa.org/) (“Web site”) or any other website that links to this policy.

#### Information Collection

We collect the information you voluntarily provide us, such as your name, phone number, email address, payment information, organization information, and any other information you choose to provide.  We may collect this information when you submit an online form, inquire into 4A’s membership or submit a membership application, volunteer for a program, register for an event, send us an e-mail, or interact with us for any other purpose.  If you create an account with us, we also collect your username and password.

When you visit our Web site, we will gather and store information about your visit automatically.  The types of information we automatically collect include the following:

  * The Internet domain (for example, “xcompany.com” if you use a private Internet access account, or “yourschool.edu” if you connect from a university’s domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our Web site;
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;
  * The date and time you access our site;
  * The pages you visit;
  * The search term(s) used in our search engine; and
  * If you linked to the 4A’s Web site from another Web site, the address of that Web site.

#### Information Use

We may use the information we collect for any lawful purpose, including the instances provided below:

  * To respond to your inquiry, or provide information you have requested;
  * To fulfill your order or request;
  * To consider a Patent of Interest you submit to the Patent Forum section of the Web site, and to post certain submissions on the Web site;
  * To operate and improve the Web site, including to make it more useful to visitors;
  * To send offers and advertising from us, our affiliates, and third parties;
  * To provide and personalize communications and content to you;
  * To comply with law and to maintain the security of our Web site; and
  * As otherwise disclosed at the time of collection or use.

Where we intend to process your personal information for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was collected, we will provide you with information regarding the purpose for the processing, as well as other relevant information, prior to processing your personal information for the new purpose.

#### Information Sharing

If the 4A’s combines with another organization or otherwise disposes of its assets (such as, for example, in a bankruptcy proceeding), another entity may acquire from the 4A’s the user information we have previously collected.  We share information with our service providers, specifically third parties who assist us with web hosting and association management software. We share information pursuant to a subpoena, court order, governmental inquiry, or other legal process or as otherwise required by law, or to protect our rights or the rights of third parties.  We also share information with your consent or as otherwise disclosed at the time of data collection or sharing.

We may share information that has been de-identified or aggregated, or any other technical information, without limitation.

#### International Visitors

This section applies to those that visit our Web site from the European Economic Area or Switzerland.

4A’s processes personal information with your consent (e.g., when 4A’s processes personal information to provide you with information you request).

On other occasions, 4A’s may process personal information when it needs to do this to fulfill a contract (e.g., to process membership applications or event registrations) or where required to do this by law.

If necessary, 4A’s may also process personal information when it is in our legitimate interests to do this (e.g., for customer service) and when these interests are not overridden by your data protection rights.

Please be aware that the personal information we collect may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province, country, or other jurisdiction, where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your location. If you are located outside of the United States, please be advised that we process and store personal information in the United States.

You have a right to the following:

  * To request access to the personal information we hold about you;
  * To request that we rectify or erase your personal information;
  * To request that we restrict or block the processing of your personal information;
  * Under certain circumstances, to receive personal information about you that we store and transmit to another without hindrance from us, including requesting that we provide your personal information directly to another, i.e., a right to data portability; and
  * Where we previously obtained your consent, to withdraw consent to processing your personal information.

To exercise these rights, contact us using the information provided in the “Contact” section below.  Please be aware that 4A’s may be unable to afford these rights to you under certain circumstances, such as if we are legally prevented from doing so.

Additionally, you have the right to lodge a complaint against us.  To do so, contact the supervisory authority in your country of residence.

#### Retention

We will process and store your information only for the period necessary to achieve the purpose of the storage, or as permitted by law.  The criteria used to determine the period of storage of information is the respective statutory retention period or as long as reasonable to fulfill a lawful purpose. After expiration of that period, the corresponding information is routinely deleted, as long as it is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of a contract or the initiation of a contract.

#### Third-Party Links and Tools

We may work with third parties that collect data about your use of the Web site and other sites or apps over time for non-advertising purposes.  The 4A’s uses Google Analytics and other third-party services to improve the performance of the Web site and for analytics and marketing purposes.  For more information about how Google Analytics collects and uses data when you use our Web site, visit <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners>/, and to opt out of Google Analytics, visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

The Web site may provide links to third-party websites or apps, including our social media pages.  We do not control the privacy practices of those websites or apps, and they are not covered by this privacy policy.  You should review the privacy policies of other websites or apps that you use to learn about their data practices.

The Web site may also include integrated social media tools or “plug-ins,” such as social networking tools offered by third parties.  If you use these tools to share personal information or you otherwise interact with these features on the Web site, those companies may collect information about you and may use and share such information in accordance with your account settings, including by sharing such information with the general public.  Your interactions with third-party companies and your use of their features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide those features.  We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policies of any accounts you create and use.

#### Your Choices

To opt out of our e-mail marketing or cancel your subscription to a marketing newsletter, you can email us at [webmaster@aaaa.org](mailto:webmaster@aaaa.org).

When you visit the Web site, advertising companies may collect information about your visits to this site and elsewhere to tailor advertising.  This type of advertising is known as interest-based advertising. Please visit www.aboutads.info to learn more about this type of advertising and to opt out of this type advertising by companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance self-regulatory program. 4As adheres to the DAA Principles.

#### Updating Your Information

To review and/or modify any of your personal information that you provide during registration, or any other voluntarily provided information, please contact us using the information in the “Contact” section below.

You may also request to review and update the personal information you have provided us.  To do so, you should send an e-mail to webmaster@aaaa.org requesting that (a) we provide a copy of your profile of personal information, and/or (b) we update or modify certain personal information.

#### Changes to This Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change our policies regarding the privacy of your personal information in the future. If that happens, we will endeavor to promptly update this privacy policy.  We encourage you to visit this page to learn of any updates.

#### Contact

If you have questions, comments, or concerns about this privacy policy, please contact us, in our role as data controller, using the following information:

Our postal address is 1065 Avenue of the Americas, 16th Floor, New York, NY 10018.

We can be reached via e-mail at [webmaster@aaaa.org](mailto:webmaster@aaaa.org) or you can reach us by telephone at (212) 682-2500.
